Could you hide a deadly secret?
Paranoid Park is a drama, crime, mystery film directed by Gus Van Sant.
A teenage skateboarder becomes suspected of being connected with a security guard
who suffered a brutal death in a skate park called "Paranoid Park".
Alex, played by Gabe Nevins.
Detective Richard Liu, played by Dan Liu.
Jared, played by Jake Miller.
Jennifer, played by Taylor Momsen.
Macy, played by Lauren McKinney.
Scratch, played by Scott Patrick Green.
Paranoid Park is a 2007 coming-of-age teen drama film
written, directed and edited by Gus Van Sant.
The film is based on the novel of the same name by Blake
Nelson and takes place in Portland, Oregon.
It is the story of a teenage skateboarder (played by Gabe Nevins) set against
the backdrop of a police investigation into a mysterious death.
Van Sant wrote the draft script in two days after
reading and deciding to adapt Nelson's novel.
To cast the film's youths, Van Sant posted an open casting call on social networking website MySpace inviting
teenagers to audition for speaking roles, as well as experienced skateboarders to act as extras.
Filming began in October 2006 and took place at
various locations in and around Portland.
Scenes at the fictional Eastside Skatepark were filmed at Burnside Skatepark
which was, like Eastside, built illegally by skateboarders.
Paranoid Park premiered on May 21, at the 2007 Cannes Film Festival
and was given a limited release on March 7, 2008.
It grossed over US$4,481,000 from its $3 million budget.
The film received mostly positive reviews; some critics praised the direction and cinematography in
particular, though others believed the film to be overly stylized and slow paced.
It won one Independent Spirit Award, two Boston Society of Film Critics awards
and the Cannes Film Festival's special 60th anniversary prize.
The film explores themes of skateboarding, portland, oregon,
trauma, male friendship, loss of virginity.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.